what's up everybody phil blackman with
barbadon.com and today we're going to
talk about the heaviest bench presses of
all time in competition we're going to
go over the raw single ply multiply and
unlimited bench presses the heaviest
ever before we do if you want to learn
anything about those bench presses just
head over to google type in bar ben
bench press and all of that information
is going to come up the second lift in
any sanctioned power lifting competition
following the squat and preceding the
deadlift is the bench press the
foundation of the bench press is widely
credited to george hackenschmidt but was
an underused lift until the 1940s but
nowadays the bench press is performed in
training and competition as both a raw
and equipped lift some notable athletes
are specialists in this lift such as raw
bench press record holder julius maddox
before we jump into each of the heaviest
bench presses ever performed in
competition let's talk about what raw
versus equipped bench pressing is raw
power lifting and competition generally
means no additional equipment is used
however most raw power lifting
competitions may allow approved lifting
belts wrist straps knee sleeves or chalk
single ply and multiply suits generate
elasticity and therefore more strength
it's considered equipped power lifting a
single ply suit has one layer of fabric
while multiply suits have two or more
layers of fabric if a contest allows for
unlimited equipment lifters can wear any
bench press shirt with no restrictions
so let's dive into the heaviest bench
presses of all time starting in raw
power lifting of course julius maddox
has the world record at 355 kilograms or
782.6 pounds maddox is seemingly in a
class by himself ever since he claimed
the raw bench press world record from
kirill sarakichev in august of 2019.
maddox lifted 335.5 kilograms or
739.7 pounds a half kilogram more than
that now second heaviest bench press of
335 kilograms or 738.5
pounds since standing atop the raw bench
press throne maddox's sights have been
set on being the first human to ever
score a raw
362.9 kilogram or 800 pound bench press
he attempted that milestone at the
beasts of the bench event on the world
ultimate strong man feats of strength
series in june 2020 but was unable to
make a legitimate attempt due to a
misload moving over to the heaviest
female raw bench press of all time it
belongs to april mathis she currently
holds the raw squat world record of
278.9 kilograms or 614.7 pounds in
addition to the raw bench press world
record of
207.5 kilograms or
457.5 pounds she hit that world record
at the 2016 southern powerlifting
federation grit miss classic and it was
a seriously impressive lift moving over
into equipped power lifting jimmy kolb
in single ply lifted
kilograms or 1120
pounds he scored that all-time heaviest
single-ply bench press at the 2021
international powerlifting association
strength spectacular powerlifting
championships on june 27 2021 at the
york barbell club in york pennsylvania
this lift was a jaw-dropping leap in
weight from the previous all-time world
record of 455 kilograms or 1003 pounds
by blaine sumner sumner scored that
previous world record in the super
heavyweight division but cole's all-time
world record now was scored in the 140
kilogram class really really impressive
stuff jimmy cole with the all-time
heaviest bench press ever moving over to
the female single player bench press
world record ray ann covenauer miller
scored the heaviest female single pie
bench press of all time
274.4 kilograms or 605 pounds at the
2021 metal militia national powerlifting
invitational at the bayfront convention
center in erie pennsylvania she competed
in the 90-plus kilogram weight class she
advanced the previous world record held
by becca swanson which stood for 13
years and four months by 1.9 kilograms
moving into the multiply power lifting
division the world record belongs to
tiny meeker he lifted 500 kilos or
1102.3 pounds since making his
competitive powerlifting debut at age 24
in 1996 meeker has competed in 77
sanctioned meets every event where he
posted a total he finished on the podium
moving over to the female division the
world record multiplied bench press
belongs to becca swanson
272.5 kilograms or 600.8 pounds she
scored that lift at the 2008 american
powerlifting federation big iron
in-house open held on march 8 2008. if
you watch swanson's lift you can see the
eccentric motion of the lift moves at a
glacial pace a testament to the control
she maintained throughout the lift all
the way to the lockout really impressive
stuff moving over into the unlimited
category in 2021 meeker was actually the
promoter of the international
powerlifting association baddest
benchers contest which saw power lifter
will barati stand atop the podium via a
501.2 kilogram or 1 105 pound bench
press katrina bialomiza with a
275.5 kilogram or 607.4 pound bench
press is the all-time world record in
the unlimited division for the women's
categories she scored that remarkable
lift at the 2021 revolution power
lifting syndicate main state power
lifting championships on september 18
2021. the current bench press world
records are extremely heavy however
there still appears to be room for those
records to grow considering colb maddox
beulomiza and kaufenhauer miller hit
their current world records in 2021.
who knows how heavy the lifts will go in
2022. the potential for the first ever
800 pound raw bench press could be on
the horizon when julius maddox squares
off in a bench press battle against
danielle zamani at iron wars 5 on
january 24th 2022 so although the record
books are forever the records within
them are not and there is a lot of heavy
bench pressing still to come i'm excited
to see if anybody particularly maddox or
zamani can pull off an 800 pound raw
bench press but until then i'm phil
bleckman for barbin.com thanks for
watching
you